Guide to the New Orleans Collection 1770-1904 (bulk 1804-1836) MS 1944
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
New Orleans Collection
1770-1904 (bulk 1804-1836)
MS 1944
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
4.5 Linear feet (10 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
The New Orleans Collection documents the expansion, maintenance, and administration of the city during the antebellum period, especially 1804-1836. The bulk of the collection is in French; items are also in English, and, occasionally, Spanish. Included in the New Orleans Collection are numerous contracts and surveyor reports; financial documents; petitions, reports, and financial documents of the Spanish Cabildo; letters and petitions to the mayor and the City Council; City Council resolutions; payroll records for city workers; levee dues records, cargo manifests, and bills of lading; license bonds; tax receipts and reports; property and land records; depositions given before the mayor; Garde de Ville and commissary reports; fire company rosters; medical reports; and correspondence. Many of these items are contemporary copies.
Provenance
Purchase, Charles F. Heartman, 1943
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Historical Note
(Events in the city's history most relevant to items in collection)
1718 New Orleans founded by John-Baptiste Le Moyne, as capital of the French territory of Louisiana
1764 Louisiana ceded to Spain
1766 Spain takes possession, establishes the Cabildo (City Council)
1785 Census of New Orleans reports 4,980 inhabitants
1800 Spain cedes territory back to France
1803 April France agrees to sell Louisiana to the U.S.
1803 Nov. 30 Territory is transferred from Spain to France
1803 Dec. 20 Territory transferred to the U.S.
1805 City of New Orleans is incorporated; municipal government consists of Mayor, Recorder, Treasurer, and Conseil de Ville (City Council) with 14 Aldermen
1805 Census of New Orleans reports 8,212
1806 Garde de Ville (police force) established
1810 Census reports 24,552
1812 First steamboat arrives in New Orleans; city soon becomes a major early nineteenth-century port
1815 Jan. 8 Battle of New Orleans fought against the British, tail end of the War of 1812
1817 Yellow fever outbreak; Board of Health established
1821 Street lighting efforts begun
1822 City waterworks project completed
1832, 1833 Cholera and yellow fever outbreaks
1833 City of Lafayette founded; absorbed by New Orleans in 1852
1835-1842 Banking capital of New Orleans exceeds New York's
1836-1852 New city charter divides New Orleans into three separate municipalities (First Municipality, Second Municipality, Third Municipality); one mayor still serves
1840 Population 102,192; second largest port in U.S. behind New York
1845 City of Carrollton founded; absorbed by New Orleans in 1874
1861 Jan. 26 Louisiana secedes from Union
1862 Apr. Union troops capture New Orleans
(Sources: Herbert Asbury, The French Quarter; Henry Rightor, ed., Standard History of New Orleans, Louisiana (1900); Gilbert C. Din and John E. Harkins, The New Orleans Cabildo: Colonial Louisiana's First City Government, 1769-1803; Louisiana State Museum, The Cabildo: Two Centuries of Louisiana History [http://lsm.crt.state.la.us/cabildo/cabildo.htm]; Kimberly Hanger, A Medley of Cultures: Louisiana History at the Cabildo.)
French words frequently found in collection:
Arrete Agreed upon, decreed
Bail a loyer Lease of house, etc.
Banquette Sidewalk
Bienfaisance Charity
Cercueil Coffin
Charrette Cart
Chemin Path, road, route
Doit Debit/debtor side of account
Droit Right, equity; right to claim, title, fee, due (tax), duty, customs duty
Esclave/esclavage: Slave/slavery
Faubourg Suburb
Geole Jail
Mairie Mayor
Pension Boarding house
Poste Post/station; guardhouse
Rapport Report/account
Tombereaux Carts
Vente Sale
Voyer Surveyor/inspector
Mayors of New Orleans, frequently found in collection:
Nov. 30, 1803-May 26, 1804 John Etienne Bore
June 2, 1804-July 26, 1805 James Pitot
July 27, 1805-March 8, 1807 John Watkins
March 9, 1807-May 16, 1812 James Mather
May 16, 1812-Oct. 8, 1812 Charles Trudeau (acting)
Nov. 6, 1812-Dec. 4, 1812 LeBreton Dorgenois (acting)
Oct. 8, 1812-Sept. 4, 1815 Nicholas Girod
Sept. 4, 1815-May 13, 1820 Augustin Macarty
May 14, 1820-May 10, 1828 Joseph Roffignac
May 12, 1828-Apr. 9, 1838 Denis Prieur
(Source: New Orleans Public Library, City Archives & Louisiana Division Special Collections, Fact Finder, http://nutrias.org/~nopl/facts/mayors.htm)
Scope and Content Note
The New Orleans Collection documents the expansion, maintenance, and administration of the city during the antebellum period, especially 1804-1836. The bulk of the collection is in French; items are also in English, and, occasionally, Spanish. Included in the New Orleans Collection are numerous contracts and surveyor reports that detail the construction and repair needs of bridges, streets, levees, canals, sidewalks, and buildings in the Vieux Carre, Faubourgs Marigny and St. Mary, and Bayou St. John. Financial documents for city accounts, such as bills, receipts, and promissory notes, further itemize construction work completed and materials used.
Also included in this collection are petitions, reports, and financial documents of the Spanish Cabildo; letters and petitions to the mayor and the City Council; City Council resolutions; payroll records for city workers; levee dues records, cargo manifests, and bills of lading; license bonds; tax receipts and reports; property and land records; depositions given before the mayor; Garde de Ville and commissary reports; fire company rosters; medical reports; and correspondence. Many of these items are contemporary copies.
This collection supports research in the history of New Orleans, particularly in the physical expansion and maintenance of the antebellum city, and in the regulation of public life and work. As the majority of material is municipal, few items are personal in nature. However, citizens' private concerns and activities are expressed in letters and petitions to the mayor and City Council, in depositions given before the mayor, and in reports of the Garde de Ville. Items relating to the yellow fever outbreak of 1817, hospital administration, and the Board of Health can be found among the letters and petitions to the mayor and City Council, and in a small series of medical reports.
Few items in the New Orleans Collection deal directly with slavery or free persons of color, with social or religious organizations, or with military activities.
Arrangement
The New Orleans Collection is organized into nineteen series:
Series I. Cabildo Records, 1770-1819, undated
Series II. Mayoral Records, 1804-1854
Series III. City Council Records, 1805-1858, undated
Series IV. Public Works Records, 1804-1861 (bulk 1820s)
Series V. Shipping Records, 1802-1875, undated
Series VI. License Bonds, 1816-1861 (bulk 1836)
Series VII. Financial Records, 1803-1883 (bulk 1820s)
Series VIII. Property Records, 1807-1888
Series IX. Legal Records, 1807-1868
Series X. Police Department Reports, 1808-1825
Series XI. Fire Department Rosters, 1861-1862 (bulk Oct. 1862)
Series XII. Medical Reports, 1813, 1817, 1830
Series XIII. Correspondence, 1805-1879, 1904
Series XIV. Freemason Documents, 1868
Series XV. Education Records: Invoices for School Books, 1841, 1848
Series XVI. Poetry, undated
Series XVII. Military Certificate, 1859
Series XVIII. Railroad Images, undated
Series XIX. Fragments, undated
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
Leverich Papers
R. R. Livingston Papers
Judge Edward Henry Durrell Papers
See Manuscript Department card catalog under New Orleans for individual items in various collections.
New Orleans (La.). --Cabildo; New Orleans (La.). --City Council; New Orleans (La.). --City Guard; New Orleans (La.). --Office of the Mayor; New Orleans (La.). Cabildo; New Orleans (La.). City Council; New Orleans (La.). City Guard; New Orleans (La.). Office of the Mayor; New Orleans (La.); Bills of lading; Bonds; City planning--Louisiana--New Orleans; Contracts; Correspondence; Depositions; Financial records; Land surveys; Licenses; Municipal government--Louisiana--New Orleans; New Orleans (La.)--History; New Orleans (La.)--Politics and government; Payroll records; Petitions; Promissory notes; Property records; Public health--Louisiana--New Orleans; Public works--Louisiana--New Orleans; Receipts; Reports; Resolutions; Ships' manifests; Tax records
- Series I. Cabildo Records, 1770-1819, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Bulk in Spanish. Includes petitions, reports, accounts, receipts, and promissory notes, most of which relate to city finances. Also later copies of Cabildo documents (originals 1794-1799) signed by Cuban merchants, regarding land concession, the introduction of hemp, and other topics.
  - Petitions, reports, 1770-1794 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Petitions, reports, 1795-1799 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Petitions, reports, 1800-1803, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Financial: accounts, receipts, promissory notes, 1770-1779 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Financial: accounts, receipts, promissory notes, 1780-1789 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial: accounts, receipts, promissory notes, 1793-1799, 1802, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Later copies of Cabildo documents, Cuban merchants, 1818-1819 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II. Mayoral Records, 1804-1854
  Bulk in French. The greater part of this series is letters and petitions to the mayor, 1807-1828, regarding city contracts and municipal services including construction, payments, employment; yellow fever, Charity Hospital administration, Board of Health (esp. 1817), cemeteries; citizens' complaints; crime and the Garde de Ville; and shipping matters. Also included are a small number of letters from various mayors, as well as mayoral notices concerning city contracts, inspection, street cleaning, Garde de Ville, and the police jail. Petitions sent to both the mayor and the Conseil de Ville are located in Series III, as most were addressed by the City Council. Depositions given before the mayor, acting in capacity of Justice of the Peace, can be found in Series IX. Additional letters to mayors, from Judge Henry Bry, are also located in Series IX.
  - Letters to the mayor, Mather, 1807-1811 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters to the mayor, Girod, 1812-1815 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters to the mayor, Macarty, 1815-1819 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters to the mayor, Roffignac, 1820-1828 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters to the mayor, various, 1837, 1842, 1844, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters from the mayor, various, 1804, 1813, 1823, 1828, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Mayoral notices, memoranda, 1808-1809, 1813, 1821, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series III. City Council Records, 1805-1858, undated
  Bulk in French (1838-1858 in English). Includes letters and petitions to the City Council, resolutions, and copies of official documents. Letters and petitions to Conseil de Ville and later councils of the three municipalities concern city contracts, construction, property, regulations, administration of the Charity Hospital, fines, cemeteries, paving, lighting, St. Mary's Market, sidewalks. Resolutions (most are contemporary copies) deal with regulations for the Garde de Ville, police jail, Charity Hospital, taxes, public balls, carts, pastry cooks, tavern license bonds, sidewalks, U.S. troops in New Orleans. Also included are copies of extracts of official documents (all are English translations), probably used by the City Council, regarding the Louisiana territory, the incorporation of New Orleans, and the Cabildo.
  - Letters and petitions to Conseil de Ville, 1807-1813 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letters and petitions to Conseil de Ville, 1814-1816; 1821-1828 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters and petitions to councils of First, Second, and Third Municipalities, 1838-1858 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Resolutions, 1805-1810 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Resolutions, 1811-1827, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Copies of official documents, 1832, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series IV. Public Works Records, 1804-1861, undated (bulk 1820s)
  Bulk in French. Documents pertaining to the construction and maintenance of New Orleans, including contracts, surveyor reports, payroll records, and offers. Contracts involve the construction of levees, bridges, streets, canals; leveling earth; draining ditches; paving; maintenance of public buildings; operating carts and steamboats; collection of market and wharfage fees. Surveyor reports (most to the mayor) concern public hazards and the repair needs of bridges, sidewalks, streets, walls, buildings, and levees; also ordinance violations and filth. Vicinities mentioned include Vieux Carre, Faubourg Marigny, Faubourg St. Mary, Bayou St. John, riverbanks. Payroll records cover city cart drivers, street cleaners, pavers, carpenters, Garde de Ville, masons, lamplighters. The majority includes names, with signatures or marks. Also included are offers and proposals for city work, and a list of gas lamps.
  See also Series VII for bills, receipts, and promissory notes for city accounts, most of which pertain to construction and maintenance.
  - Reports, Surveyor, 1808-1823 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Surveyor, 1824-Sept. 1828 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Surveyor, Oct. 1828-1831, 1856-1859, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Contracts, 1804-1812 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Contracts, 1814-1821 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Contracts, 1822-1824 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Contracts, 1825-1829 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Contracts, 1830-1834, 1849 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Payroll, Garde de Ville, 1814, 1821, 1828, 1842 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Payroll, Carts, 1816, 1821-1822 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Payroll, Carts, 1823-1827, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Payroll, Carts for street cleaning, paving, 1823-1827 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Payroll, Masons, 1823-1825 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Payroll, Carpenters, 1823-1828 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Payroll, Lamplighters (Second Municipality), 1840, 1846-1849 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Payroll, Various, 1806, 1833-1837 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Offers, 1809-1822, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Letters/proposals to Surveyor, Second Municipality, 1836-1839 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - List of gas lamps, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Series V. Shipping Records, 1802-1875, undated
  Bulk in English. Records of levee dues collected, cargo manifests, bills of lading, receipts, Price Currents, market reports, and miscellaneous items. Many of the Price Currents also contain letters to customers from merchants (most Leverich & Co.).
  - Customhouse/ harbormaster fees, 1804, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Levee dues, 1816-1822, 1825 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Levee dues, 1831 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Levee dues, sea vessel arrivals, Feb.-Nov. 1833 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Levee dues, 1837-1846, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cargo manifests, imports, Second Municipality, July-Aug. 1842 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cargo manifests, imports, Second Municipality, Sept.-Nov. 1842 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cargo manifests, imports, Second Municipality, July-Nov. 1842 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Bills of lading, receipts, accounts, 1802-1806, 1838-1850 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Bills of lading, receipts, accounts, 1852-1855, 1862, 1870 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Price Currents, market reports, 1834-1867 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Tonnage measurement, Experiment, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Reports and certificates, 1805-1822 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Series VI. License Bonds, 1816-1861 (bulk 1836)
  Bulk in English. Records (mostly printed forms) of license bonds for drays, private carts, hacks and cabs; taverns, coffee-houses, and cabarets; pensions; others. First, Second, and Third Municipalities are represented. One item, volume of licenses 1818-1819, is housed in the Manuscript Department's oversize cabinet, call phrase is Y-1818-19, New Orleans.
  - Various, including carts, cabarets, 1816 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Drays, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Drays, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Drays, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hacks and cabs, list, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Private carts, carriages, 1843, 1859, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Taverns, coffee-houses, cabarets, 1834-1836 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Taverns, coffee-houses, cabarets, 1836-1838, 1845, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Record book of various licenses including butchers, grocers, restaurants, coffee-houses, merchants, dairies, 1847-1850 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Record book of various licenses including pensions, cabarets, carts, 1818-1819 (Box Y, Folder 1818-1819)
- Series VII. Financial Records, 1803-1883, undated (bulk 1820s)
  Bulk in French. The greater part of this series consists of accounts, bills, receipts, and promissory notes of the City Corporation of New Orleans, for materials and services pertaining to the construction and maintenance of the city. Usually a single document served as a bill, a certification by the city surveyor of work completed or materials received, a promissory note, and a receipt of paymentâ??thus, these items have been sorted together. Documents that served solely as promissory notes or orders of payment (often printed) are sorted separately.
  Also included in this series are tax receipts and reports for property, coffee-houses, grog shops, billiards, etc.; tax records for legal cases; charity records; financial material (mostly receipts) of merchant and philanthropist John McDonogh; records of the Sarphy family involving a mortgage debt; and miscellaneous checks, bonds, estimates, and calculations.
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1803-1809 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1810-1814 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1815-1817 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1820-May 1821 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1821 June-Dec. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1822 Jan.-May (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1822 June-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1823 Jan.-May (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1823 June-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1824 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1825 Jan.-May (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1825 June-Dec. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1826-1827 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1828 Jan.-June (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1828 July-1829 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1830-1839 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1840-1849 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1850-1859 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Accounts, bills, receipts, 1860-1868, 1872, 1883, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Promissory notes / orders of payment, 1806-1820 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Promissory notes / orders of payment, 1821-1824 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Promissory notes / orders of payment, 1825-1830, 1835, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Tax receipts, property, City of New Orleans, 1825-1828 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tax receipts, property, Parish of Orleans, 1834, 1842-1844 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tax receipts, property, Parish of Jefferson, 1827, 1829 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tax receipts, property, City of Lafayette, 1838 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tax receipts, property, Town of Carrollton, 1847-1851 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tax receipts, various (coffee-house, billiards, hawkers, etc.), Parish of Orleans, 1831, 1834, 1843-1845 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tax report, grog shops, merchants, balls, hotels, boarding houses, etc., 1838 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified (probably report of butchers tax/fees), includes proprietor, street, amount, observations, 1831 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Tax / court fee receipts and reports, District and Supreme Courts, 1814-1816, 1824-1828, 1832 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Tax report, unidentified attorney, 1831-1835 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Tax documents, miscellaneous, 1808, 1826, 1838-1839 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Charity records, orders of payment, 1816-1819, 1825 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Charity records, reports, 1825, 1828, 1835 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - John McDonogh, financial records, 1802-1857 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sarphy family, financial / property records, 1852-1865 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Checks, 1804 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Bonds, 1836, 1868, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Estimates, calculations, 1822, 1836, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Series VIII. Property Records, 1807-1888, undated
  Bulk in French. Documents and copies (bulk) of documents pertaining to property in New Orleans, especially the sale and transfer of lots, and to land in Louisiana, including letters to the General Land Office, patents, certificates, surveys, and inspections. Also copies of documents detailing the sale of land by Bernard Marigny to the city of New Orleans, and documents of (mostly letters to) Columbus Lawson, Register of the Land Office at New Orleans.
  - Property records, New Orleans, 1807-1818 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Property records, New Orleans, 1820-1837, 1869, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bernard Marigny, sale of land (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Estimates, land, faubourgs de la Course, Annunciation, 1822 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Land records and letters, Louisiana State, 1808-1888, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Columbus Lawson, Register of Land Office, 1809-1814 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series IX. Legal Records, 1807-1868, undated
  French and English. The bulk of this series consists of depositions given before the Mayor, acting in the capacity as Justice of the Peace. Cases involve theft, trespassing, verbal threats, threatening behavior, assaults, gambling, alcohol, maritime deserters, the mutinous behavior of sailors, indentured servitude, runaway slaves, public balls, domestic violence, and dueling.
  This series also contains summonses, discharge notices, power of attorney forms, documents relating to free persons of color (proof of residency, character witness), recognizances, a copy of a will, and legal documents (many are copies) pertaining to cases in New Orleans, Louisiana, Pennsylvania, and New York. Also included are correspondence and the legal papers of Judge Joshua Lewis and Judge Henry Bry.
  - Depositions, 1807-1809 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Depositions, 1810 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Depositions, 1811 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Depositions, 1812 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Depositions, 1813 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Depositions, 1814-1816 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Depositions, 1817 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Depositions, 1818-1819 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Depositions, 1820 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Depositions, 1821 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Depositions, 1822 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Depositions, 1824 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Depositions, 1825 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Depositions, 1829, 1832 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Depositions, [1812-1820] (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Depositions, [1820-1828] (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Depositions, Undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Summonses/discharges, 1810-1844 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Free persons of color documents, 1844-1845 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Power of Attorney forms, 1823-1829, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Recognizances, 1813, 1816, 1825 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Will, Heloise Baudouin (copy), 1865 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous legal records, 1812-1868, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Judge Joshua Lewis, correspondence, 1807-1830, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Judge Joshua Lewis, legal documents, 1819-1833, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Judge Henry Bry, correspondence, legal documents, 1832-1842, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Series X. Police Department Reports, 1808-1825
  In French. Reports Garde de Ville, captain and commissary reports, especially faubourgs St. Mary and Marigny, detailing activities, arrests, complaints. Includes mention of Marie Laveau (8/15/1824). See also Series IV for payroll records for the Garde de Ville.